Hrvoje Šimić

Full Stack Developer

Zagreb, Croatia

shime shime shimetweets



Full stack JavaScript developer with 5+ years of experience. Worked with various US based startups over the years and made some commits to Ruby on Rails core. Focused on working with small teams and building small products from the ground up.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer at Synectics Media

April 2016 - Current

http://synecticsmedia.com/

Currently building an online marketplace focused on automotive parts and primarily intended for mobile use.

- Built an MVP from scratch using Ember.js and Ruby on Rails
- Implemented integration with peer to peer payment services using both PayPal and Stripe

Full Stack Developer at Airbrake

January 2016 - April 2016

https://airbrake.io

Airbrake is the first and the most popular exception tracking service.

Maintained their open-source JavaScript and Node.js libraries with thousands of downloads

Full Stack Developer at Lessonhub

January 2015 - January 2016

https://www.catapulthub.com/

Lessonhub is a custom education-focused content management system used by teachers across the US.

- Built a custom content management system from scratch, with support for math functions and various custom lesson elements, used by teachers for their educational purposes every day
- Implemented frontend in Ember.is and the backend in Ruby on Rails
- Was in charge of everything related to development, including managing other people that worked on the project

Full Stack Developer at Particle

October 2013 - January 2015

https://www.particle.io/

Particle is an internet of things cloud platform with a focus of providing easy internet access to Arduino-like boards.

- Built a custom browser-based IDE for their platform from scratch, using Ember.js that communicated with multiple APIs
- Built a Rails API with support for submissions of custom third party libraries for the IDE usage

Backend Developer at Betterdoc

August 2013 - October 2013

https://www.betterdoc.org/

Betterdoc is a SaaS that helps its customers with finding the best doctor for their needs.

Improved the test suite and raised the quality of the existing Ruby on Rails codebase

Full Stack Developer at Hiiro

February 2013 - May 2013

Hiiro was a SaaS for finding high quality contractors, meant to be an alternative to Toptal. Unfortunately, it didn't gain enough traction, so development was discontinued.

- Implemented private exception tracking system for the Ruby on Rails API
- Implemented various features using TDD for frontend that was using Angular.js and the backend which was using

Ruby on Rails

Refactored large portion of codebase which improved the performance of the API

Backend Developer at Rackspace

February 2012 - August 2013

https://rackspace.com

Rackspace is a popular cloud provider and I worked on Airbrake. Airbrake is the first and the most popular exception tracking service.

- Implemented various third party service integrations like Engineyard, Heroku and Jira using TDD
- Maintained an open source Ruby gem that integrates with Rails with millions of downloads
- Added support for newer versions of Rails to an open source gem
- Resolved support issues for over 40,000 monthly active users

Full Stack Developer at Showmojo

September 2011 - February 2012

http://showmojo.com

Showmojo is a small website for managing real estate showings. Backend is written in Ruby on Rails and the frontend is using jQuery.

- Implemented analytics for images rendered on third-party services
- Implemented various CSS and JavaScript hacks for IE6
- Improved user experience for photo uploads

VOLUNTEER

Author, Maintainer at Open source

September 2011 - Current

Actively contributing and raising quality of open source software.

- Contributed to Ruby on Rails and made it to top 200 Ruby on Rails contributors of all time
- Maintained multiple Ruby gems with millions of downloads
- Authored multiple NPM packages with thousands of downloads
- Authored a popular Markdown preview tool

Co-organizer at JavaScript Zagreb

October 2015 - Current

JavaScript users meetup group for Zagreb, Croatia. http://www.meetup.com/JavaScript-Zagreb/

- Co-organized dozens of meetups in various places
- Gave multiple talks about testing and Ember.js

Co-organizer at NodeSchool Zagreb

May 2015 - Current

NodeSchool chapter for Zagreb, Croatia.

http://nodeschool.io/zagreb

Co-hosted dozens of events for teaching programming

Organizer at Ruby Zagreb

March 2014 - October 2015

Ruby users meetup group for Zagreb, Croatia.

http://www.meetup.com/rubyzg/

- Started Ruby meetups in Zagreb, Croatia and organized dozens of meetups and drinkups
- Gave a couple of talks about various Ruby topics

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science at University of Zagreb

2008 - 2013

LANGUAGES -

English Fluent Croatian

Native Speaker